

Anna Taylor

Certified Medical Assistant

Meticulous, patient-focused Certified Medical Assistant with 10+ years of extensive experience in providing a variety of healthcare services and administrative assistant to support organizational objectives. Possess a genuine passion for delivering premium, compassionate patient care, and helping diverse people within the healthcare industry. Exceptionally organized and focused, adept at managing multiple responsibilities in a fast-paced and high-stressing environment.

anna@novoresume.com

0123 2020 9876



O Houston, TX

in linkedin.com/in/anna.taylor

WORK EXPERIENCE

Medical Assistant

First Choice Health Institute &

08/2015 - Present

Dallas, TX

- Support the implementation of quality assurance and control program to guarantee proper compliance with the OSHA, HIPAA, and CLIA regulations, resulting in improved patient satisfaction and a 12% decrease in overhead
- Maintain and enhance the organization's credibility by ensuring the cleanliness and sanitation of all facilities, equipment, and exam rooms.
- Oversee multiple related responsibilities with a high level of proficiency, such as taking the patient's vital signs and medical history, as well as performing injections, venipunctures, and ancillary tests per organization's established guidelines.
- Demonstrate independence and efficiency in handling various administrative duties, including maintaining medical records and scheduling appointments, among others, enabling doctors and staff to focus on patient' healthcare concerns.
- Contribute as a pivotal member of the interdisciplinary healthcare team by providing ongoing assistance to 20+ medical doctors, physician associates, and staff nurses to guarantee seamless office operations and optimal patient care.

Medical Assistant

Priority Heartbeat Medical Services

02/2011 - 06/2015

Houston, TX

- Monitored periodically and recorded the patient's vital signs, test results, and other information for proper documentation while asserting strict confidentiality.
- Accommodated the patient's and doctor's request regarding various concerns/matters related to diet programs, nutritional supplements, treatment procedures, and medical supplies availability.
- Maintained records of patients' health progress and communicated with the patients and their families to explain the medical procedure as well as the prescribed diet and medications for their continuous recovery.

Medical Office Assistant Health & Wealth Medical Center

06/2008 - 01/2011

Houston, TX

- Professionally attended to more than 40 patients daily through the center's phone system and appointment calendar.
- Assisted in conducting examinations and necessary lab tests for more than 500 patients and accurately recorded the results into the center's database.
- Interacted closely with patients to take and record their vital signs and biopsies, such as heart rate and blood pressure.

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Administrative Support

CERTIFICATES

Certified Phlebotomy Technician 2

National Healthcareer Association

CPR & First Aid Training G

eCPRcertification.com

Medical Billing and Coding Certification ☑

American Academy of Professional Coders (AAPC)

American Association of Medical Assistants (AAMA)

Advanced Care Life Support Certification American Heart Association

Basic Life Support Certification 🗗

American Heart Association

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Healthcare Management

University of Houston

2005 - 2008

LANGUAGES







English

Spanish

French

